Junxiao **Wang** LLM Researcher | Developer/Engineer Python/PyTorch

i Born Weihai, China, September 11, 1991



Several years of experience applying machine learning models *efficiently*, *securely*, and *privately* in distributed systems. Enjoys contributing to open source and tech communities by sharing knowledge and experience. Interested in designing better problem-solving methods for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools.



Programming Python (PyTorch), Golang, Java, C/C++

Machine Learning Mixture of Experts, Quantization, Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning, Federated Learning

CV/NLP/Multimodal Diffusion, GAN, VAE, VIT, CNN, GPT, BERT, GNN, CLIP

PC/Reviewers AISTAT24, ICCV23, TMC, TNSE, etc.

Misc Tools Git, LaTex, Linux

</> Projects & Experiences

Feb 2024 Feb 2023

Pre-Trained Models, KAUST, Python (PyTorch)

- > Implementation of efficient GPT Inference with Quantization and MoE Offloading.
- > Implanting triggerable but invisible *Trojans* in BERT via random encoding perturbation.
- > Slow-Learning Modality Rebalance based on Prototype implemented with Python.
- > Implementation of Diffusion Concept Negation with test-time attention refinement.
- > Publications: KDD23, NeurlPS23, CVPR23.
- > **\O**: Modal-Imbalance-PMR, TrojanAttack.

Quantization MoE Offloading Trojan Modality Prototype Concept Diffusion

Mar 2023 Mar 2021

Distributed Machine Learning, Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Python (PyTorch)

- > *Gradient Protection* based on Random Matrix theory implemented with Python.
- > Knowledge Editing based on TF-IDF and Filter Pruning implemented with NNI.
- > Implementation of CLIP based *Distributed Framework* with Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning.
- > Publications: INFOCOM22, IJCAI22, WWW22, WWW23, TMC, Network.
- > **\O**: GradDefense, Unlearning, PromptFL.

Gradient Random Matrix TF-IDF Filter Pruning NNI CLIP Parameter-Efficient Fine-Tuning

Sep 2019 Sep 2018

Network Intelligence, QMUL, Python/C/C++

- > Online *Traffic Recognition* based on 1D-CNN implemented with TensorFlow and Keras.
- > Implementation of adaptive Sketch Memory Allocation with Actor-Critic Framework.
- > Implementation of *RFID Integrity Authentication* with protocol design.
- > Publications: ICA3PP19, CFI19, SmartIoT19, IoTJ, TMC.
- > **\O**: TrafficCategorization, HBLSketch, RL_MemoryAllocation.

Traffic Recognition | Sketch | Memory Allocation | Actor-Critic | RFID

Dec 2020 Sep 2016

Network Systems, Dalian University of Technology, Python/Golang/Java/C/C++

- > Implementation of efficient Software Upgrade with State-Isolated Modular Management.
- > Implementation of fine-grained Control Plane Scheduling with Queue Management.
- > Data Plane Flow Tracing based on Probabilistic Packet Tagging implemented with Python.
- > Publications: SIGCOMM18 Demo, ISJ, TNSM, TNSE, IoTJ, OJCOMS.
- > **Q**: CLICK-UP, FlowTracer, NFVCloud, SDNCloud, SDNDashboard, AgileScheduler.

Software Upgrade Control Plane Scheduling Queue Data Plane Flow Tracing Packet Tagging

Employment

2023-current	Researcher, King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST), Thuwal, Saudi Arabia
2021-2023	Researcher, Hong Kong Polytechnic University (PolyU), Hong Kong, China

2018-2019 Researcher, Queen Mary University of London (QMUL), London, United Kingdom

Education

- 2020 PhD in Computer Science, Dalian University of Technology (DUT), Dalian, China
- 2017 MEng in Computer Science, Dalian University of Technology (DUT), Dalian, China
- 2014 BEng in Software Engineering, Dalian Maritime University (DMU), Dalian, China

Publications

- > Peiran Dong, Song Guo, <u>Junxiao Wang</u> (Corresponding Author), Bingjie Wang, Jiewei Zhang, Ziming Liu. Towards Test-Time Refusals via Concept Negation. The Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2023, New Orleans, LA, USA. (acceptance rate~26.1% [3,222/12,343])
- > Tao Guo, Song Guo, Junxiao Wang (Corresponding Author), Xueyang Tang, Wenchao Xu. PromptFL: Let Federated Participants Cooperatively Learn Prompts Instead of Models Federated Learning in Age of Foundation Model. IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing (TMC) 2023.
- > Peiran Dong, Song Guo, Junxiao Wang (Corresponding Author). Investigating Trojan Attacks on Pre-trained Language Model-powered Database Middleware. ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD) 2023, Long Beach, CA, USA. (acceptance rate~22.1% [313/1,416])
- > Yunfeng Fan, Wenchao Xu, Haozhao Wang, Junxiao Wang, Song Guo. PMR: Prototypical Modal Rebalance for Multimodal Learning. IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2023, Vancouver, Canada. (acceptance rate~25.8% [2,360/9,155])
- > Tao Guo, Song Guo, Junxiao Wang (Corresponding Author). pFedPrompt: Learning Personalized Prompt for Vision-Language Models in Federated Learning. The ACM Web Conference (WWW) 2023, Austin, Texas, USA. (acceptance rate~19.2% [365/1,900])
- > Leijie Wu, Song Guo, <u>Junxiao Wang</u> (Corresponding Author), Zicong Hong, Jie Zhang, Yaohong Ding. Federated Unlearning: Guarantee the Right of Clients to Forget. IEEE Network 2022.
- > Xin Xie, Xiulong Liu, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, Song Guo, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li. Efficient Integrity Authentication Scheme for Large-scale RFID Systems. IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing (TMC) 2022.
- > Rui Zhang, Song Guo, <u>Junxiao Wang</u> (Corresponding Author), Xin Xie, Dacheng Tao. A Survey on Gradient Inversion: Attacks, Defenses and Future Directions. International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2022, Vienna, Austria. (acceptance rate~14.9% [679/4,535])
- > Junxiao Wang, Song Guo, Xin Xie, Heng Qi. Federated Unlearning via Class-Discriminative Pruning. The ACM Web Conference (WWW) 2022, Online. (acceptance rate~17.7% [323/1,822])
- > Junxiao Wang, Song Guo, Xin Xie, Heng Qi. Protect Privacy from Gradient Leakage Attack in Federated Learning. IEEE International Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM) 2022, Online. (acceptance rate~19.8% [224/1,129])
- > Heng Qi, Junxiao Wang, Wenxin Li, Yuxin Wang, Tie Qiu. A Blockchain-driven IIoT Traffic Classification Service for Edge Computing. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoTJ) 2021.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Wenxin Li, Keqiu Li, Steve Uhlig, Yuxin Wang. Dynamic SDN Control Plane Request Assignment in NFV Datacenters. IEEE Transactions on Network Science and Engineering (TNSE) 2021.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li, Steve Uhlig. Click-UP: Towards the Software Upgrade of Click based Modular Network Function. IEEE Systems Journal (ISJ) 2020.
- > Xinping Xu, Wenxin Li, Heng Qi, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, Keqiu Li. Latency-Constrained Cost-Minimized Request Allocation for Geodistributed Cloud Services. IEEE Open Journal of the Communications Society (OJCOMS) 2020.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Yang He, Wenxin Li, Keqiu Li. FlowTracer: An Effective Flow Trajectory Detection Solution Based on Probabilistic Packet Tagging in SDN-Enabled Networks. IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management (TNSM) 2019.
- > Keyan Zhao, Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Xin Xie, Keqiu Li. HBL-Sketch: A New Three-tier Sketch for Accurate Network Measurement. International Conference on Algorithms and Architectures for Parallel Processing (ICA3PP) 2019, Melbourne, Australia.
- > Wenrui Zhou, Yuan Cao, Heng Qi, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>. An Effective Network Intrusion Detection Framework Based on Learning to Hash. IEEE International Conference on Smart Internet of Things (SmartloT) 2019, Tianjin, China.
- > Wanqian Zhang, <u>Junxiao Wang</u>, Sheng Chen, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li. A Framework for Resource-aware Online Traffic Classification Using CNN. International Conference on Future Internet Technologies (CFI) 2019, Phuket, Thailand.
- > Junxiao Wang, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li, Xiaobo Zhou. PRSFC-IoT: A Performance and Resource Aware Orchestration System of Service Function Chaining for Internet of Things. IEEE Internet of Things Journal (IoTJ) 2018.
- > Junxiao Wang, Yuchen Huang, Heng Qi, Keqiu Li, Steve Uhlig. CLICK-UP: Towards Software Upgrades of Click-driven Stateful Network Element. ACM SIGCOMM Conference 2018 (Demo), Budapest, Hungary.